Chase Ackeret

Operations Specialist

Creative Operations Specialist with talents in executing effective operating rhythms and management systems structures. Adept at analyzing, articulating and solving various problems. Analytical and organized with the ability to work independently or as a part of a team.

Work History

2020-01 -Current

Contract Employee

New Life International, Underwood, IN

- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Modified existing databases to meet unique needs and goals determined during initial evaluation and planning process.
- Created and implemented database designs and data models.
- Trained and coached new team members on proper CNC machine set-up procedures.
- Checked prices and calculated totals for accurate invoice processing.
- Implemented organizational systems to optimize product placement and operational productivity.
- Developed and managed CNC tool library of 200+ tools to accurate maintain tool numbers and their corresponding offsets.

2018-02 -2019-12

Operations Specialist

Wolff Indiana, LLC, Columbus, IN

- Tracked and analyzed reports to determine where improvements in business could be made
- Generated reports of findings to help management with making key decisions
- Established efficient workflow processes, monitored daily productivity and implemented modifications to improve overall effectiveness of personnel and

Contact

Address

1160 Ernest Dr. Seymour, IN, 47274

Phone

(812) 216-4642

E-mail

chaseackeret@gmail.com

Skills

Microsoft Excel



Micosoft Access



Statistical Analysis / SPSS



Resource Planning and Scheduling



Database administration



Strategic Planning



Presentation design



Scheduling



activities

- Developed and implemented part numbering system to help with inventory tracking and data analysis
- Kept physical files and digitized records organized for easy updating and retrieval by authorized team members
- Production increased roughly 25% due to scheduling changes implemented
- Used Microsoft Excel to model data and forecast trends.
- Developed and updated tracking spreadsheets using Microsoft Excel.
- Created and implemented strategies for improving operational efficiency and accuracy.
- Monitored supply chain and managed all logistics functions for company.
- Monitored daily and weekly key performance indicators to maintain on-track status.

2016-04 - Family Support Specialist

Centersone Of America, Seymour, IN

- Used interactive visuals and static worksheets to teach each student algebra and writing techniques
- Reported child abuse in accordance with legal standards of mandatory reporters
- Organized activities for birth parents and in-home support counselors
- Monitored progress and documented any patient health status changes, keeping healthcare team updated
- Built solid and trusting rapport with children and families, fostering trust and communication to meet case needs
- Worked to improve and enhance patient lives through effective and compassionate care
- Documented data and completed accurate updates to case records
- Monitored progress and documented any patient health status changes, keeping healthcare team updated.
- Increased youth participation in pro-social activities

by 10-50%, depending on patient, through collaboration with therapist assistants and community resources.

2014-08 - Production Worker

2016-04

2015-10

Wolff Industries Inc., Columbus, IN

- Monitored machinery in operation to identify concerns and make corrections or report complex problems
- Used hand trucks, forklifts and scissor lifts to complete tasks and transport items
- Maintained maximum organization and productivity by properly sorting project components on work tables
- Conducted quality inspections of finished products and made minor repairs to meet project expectations
- Supported current production needs by moving items between equipment, conveyors and staging areas
- Supported machine operators in setup and operation of production equipment resulting in efficient runs
- Inspected final products to assess compliance with quality standards and established tolerances
- Organized work to meet demanding production goals with 90-100% success rate.

2011-06 - Department Head

Orscheln Farm & Home, Seymour, IN

- Assigned jobs to individual employees by considering factors such as previous training, current abilities and general knowledge
- Assisted customers with locating and choosing merchandise in any store department
- Educated customers on promotions to enhance sales
- Walked through department multiple times each shift to evaluate and correct issues such as cleaning and stock replenishment needs
- Trained team members in successful strategies to meet operational and sales targets

- Strengthened merchandising and promotional strategies to drive customer engagement and boost sales
- Implemented daily operating procedures to keep store clean, adequately stocked and well-organized
- Maintained clean, adequately stocked and organized store by streamlining daily operations and introducing new procedures
- Designed and built over 5 displays per season to generate customer interest in store merchandise.

Education

2010-08 -2015-08

Bachelor of Science: Psychology

Indiana University - Purdue University At Columbus - Columbus, iN

- Graduated with 3.5 GPA
- Member of Alpha Lamda Delta National Honor Society
- Dean's List multiple semesters